<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Gregor von Laszewski</title>
    <link>http://laszewski.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Gregor von Laszewski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Gregor von Laszewski, 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 01:42:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://laszewski.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Cloud Cluster</title>
      <link>http://laszewski.github.io/project/pi-cloud-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 01:42:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://laszewski.github.io/project/pi-cloud-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Raspberry Pi Cloud Cluster THis project is open to anyone wanting to work with me on building a Raspberry Pi Cloud Cluster. We have 100-200 Raspberry Pis which provide an ideal playground for building your own cluster and explore distributed computing algorithms on real hardware. In this project you would be building a cluster and than putting cloud software on the cluster to make it our own cloud service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIST Big Data</title>
      <link>http://laszewski.github.io/project/cloudmesh-nist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 01:42:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://laszewski.github.io/project/cloudmesh-nist/</guid>
      <description>NIST Big Data Refernce Architecture Reference architectures provide an authoritative source of information about a specific subject area that guides and constrains the instantiations of multiple architectures and solutions. Reference architectures generally serve as a foundation for solution architectures and may also be used for comparison and alignment of instantiations of architectures and solutions. The goal of the NBD-PWG Reference Architecture Subgroup is to develop an open reference architecture for Big Data that achieves the following objectives:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Impact</title>
      <link>http://laszewski.github.io/project/impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 01:42:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://laszewski.github.io/project/impact/</guid>
      <description>In scientific impact metrics we attempt to evaluate the work conducted by researcher teams or organizations and compare how they perform to other groups.
In our effort we use the bibliometrics approach to evaluate the scientific impact of XSEDE. By utilizing publication data from various sources, e.g., ISI Web of Science and Microsoft Academic Graph, we calculate the impact metrics of XSEDE publications and show how they compare with non-XSEDE publication from the same field of study, or non-organization peers from the same journal issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudmesh JavaScript User Interface</title>
      <link>http://laszewski.github.io/project/cloudmesh-gui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 01:41:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://laszewski.github.io/project/cloudmesh-gui/</guid>
      <description>Please contact me if you like to help developing a JavaScript Graphical user interface</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Cloud Mangement with Cloudmesh</title>
      <link>http://laszewski.github.io/project/cloudmesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 01:41:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://laszewski.github.io/project/cloudmesh/</guid>
      <description>Cloudmesh enables you to access multi-cloud environments such as AWS, Azure, Google, and OpenStack Cloudsvery easily. To start a vm on AWS you can say
cms set cloud=AWS cms vm boot  To start one on Azure, simply set the cloud accordingly
cms set cloud=AWS cms vm boot  Cloudmesh is an evolution of our previous tool that has been used by hundreds of students and cloud practitioners to interact easily with clouds to create a service mashup to access common cloud services across a number of cloud providers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>