<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>class | Gregor von Laszewski</title>
    <link>/tag/class/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/class/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>class</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 01:33:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hufdd866d90d76849587aac6fbf27da1ac_464_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>class</title>
      <link>/tag/class/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality teaching</title>
      <link>/post/class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 01:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/class/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may like some of the quotes from students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Best class I ever took at IU.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thanks to you I got a job at a top rated company.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My company has adopted lessons learned from your class.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The level of support and expertise the professor provides is outstanding and unmatched within IU.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All classes can be taken by graduate and undergraduate students.
Undergraduate students may need permission from me for some classes. In
the past we had dedicated undergraduates participatintg in the class
that were in the top 5% of the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;independent-study&#34;&gt;Independent Study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independent Studies are any time available for graduate and
undergraduate students.  Contact Gregor at 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:laszewski@gmail.com&#34;&gt;laszewski@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.
Independent studies will work on programming projects, advanced cloud
topics, or conference/workshop papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;undergraduate-reu&#34;&gt;Undergraduate REU&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a unique paid opportunity. It is available for US Citizens or
Permanent Residents. Strong knowledge in Linux and Python is required.
20 hour per week commitment is required. Please inqure with Gregor to
see if you are qualified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have immediate REU positions available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Coud Directory</title>
      <link>/post/vdir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 01:33:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/vdir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-directory&#34;&gt;Virtual directory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be part of a team to create a multicloud virtual directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your goal will be to to develop an API, secure REST, and commandline
tool that easily interfaces with storage servoces such as file based
services and object stores osted on the internet to create a virtual
directory that accesses the files by directory name and filename.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is espaciellyusefull for data scientists that may want to strore
their data on multiple cloud providers and eliminate vendor lockin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could also be useful for geographically distributed files that
allow services to utilize them based on speed of access or the
physical location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous version of cloudmesh we have developed an integrated
approach for compute and storage services. However in this project we
like to explore some new features and separate the implementation form
the main cloudmesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past cloudmesh has conducted two such projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudmesh.github.io/cloudmesh-manual/manual/storage.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://cloudmesh.github.io/cloudmesh-manual/manual/storage.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudmesh.github.io/cloudmesh-manual/manual/vdir.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://cloudmesh.github.io/cloudmesh-manual/manual/vdir.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to reimplement thise projects and significantly improve them by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding more providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding a secure rest service for acceassing the virdual directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a slick user interface to brows the virdula directry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put everything in a container so it can be run on Linux, MAc and
Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dreate a convenient commandline tool that allows starting of the
service, interacting with it and make this real easy to use. THe
commandline will hide the docker commands while providing human
readable abbreviations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliver unit tests with pytests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliver a high quality report including benchmarks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for you to participate in this project you will need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer on which you can run docker (Windows Home will not work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significant python knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be highly motivated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be willing to have meetings on this project once or twice a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SHowcase significant progress over the lifetime of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be knowledgable with github (a repository will be provided to which
Dr. von Laszewski will contribute)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct task management in GitHub (Gregor will explain)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be honest and not hiding problems or implementation bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must be able to do a videoconference and be able to share your screen (I typically use google meet or zoom).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;options&#34;&gt;Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the two projects used a single file taansfer logic, while the
other used a parallel file transfer option. It will be up to you to decide how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first week collect all clouds and services that could be
used in this project. THis work should be split between the
teammembers and a detailed analysis including features including
authentication and security must be conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to evaluate the previous efforts and decide how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way is to select several cloudas and define an abstraction that
has to be implemented for each cloud. this can be actually bes
demonstrated by an example commandline such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;vdir mkdir DIR
vdir cd [DIR]
vdir ls [DIR]
vdir add [FILEENDPOINT] [DIR_AND_NAME]
vdir delete [DIR_OR_NAME]
vdir status [DIR_OR_NAME]
vdir get NAME DESTINATION
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the commandline derive some API interface and use FastAPI to
implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify a mechnism on how to deal with the security. AN encrypted
file with your cloud credentials will be sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the limitations of the previous vdir project is that the
fill add function is done only on a single file but not on a
recursive file tree. Naturally we need to upload, single files,
multiple files and filetrees, similar to the unix command rsync.
This has been implemented in the storage command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;storage [--storage=SERVICE] [--parallel=N] create dir DIRECTORY
storage [--storage=SERVICE] [--parallel=N] get SOURCE DESTINATION [--recursive]
storage [--storage=SERVICE] [--parallel=N] put SOURCE DESTINATION [--recursive]
storage [--storage=SERVICE] [--parallel=N] list [SOURCE] [--recursive] [--output=OUTPUT]
storage [--storage=SERVICE] [--parallel=N] delete SOURCE
storage [--storage=SERVICE] search  DIRECTORY FILENAME [--recursive] [--output=OUTPUT]
storage [--storage=SERVICE] sync SOURCE DESTINATION [--name=NAME] [--async]
storage [--storage=SERVICE] sync status [--name=NAME]
storage config list [--output=OUTPUT]
storage [--parallel=N] copy SOURCE DESTINATION [--recursive]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like naturally to (re-)implement the storage command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you start implementing describe and showcase a couple of commands on how to used it.
Our command will be called cdir (for cloudmesh dir so it is easy to distinguish)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you provide a comprehensive list of potentail cloud
storage ervices. Distinguish between for pay and free services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list could include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS Object Store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An ssh accesible computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Degoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google docs/drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Icedrive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MEGA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MediaFire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MediaFire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mega&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OneCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OneDrive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oracle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebDAV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your local computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iDrive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;idrive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there companies or services that already offer this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
